OUR STICKY LOVE
This is so nice.
That's right!
Today's your birthday.
Is there anything you want to do?
I never thought about it.
Want to go see my family?
What?
I have family too.
A grandmother who accepts me
without any questions.
I just asked my family to return.
Do you have a problem with that?
Sisters who always have my back.
I was your closest friend in the village.
A friend with the purest of hearts, and a…
Slightly older brother-in-law.
A slightly older brother-in-law.
You can ask me to run errands
as much as you want.
And a dutiful younger brother.
I miss them all so much.
This is nice.
I'll have grilled whole potatoes,
sausage, and rice cake skewers.
What about you?
Oppa, come here.
Oppa, should we get coffee?
I want an iced mocha. You?
Oppa, do you have a hole in your chin?
This is really good.
Oppa, say "ah."
Oppa, you okay?
Jang Tae-ha.
Yeah?
I asked what you're going to eat.
Right. I'll have what you're having.
Two butter-grilled potatoes,
two sausage and rice cake skewers, please.
Here, look at this.
- Goodness, ma'am!
- Why?
- Ma'am.
- Did you go grocery shopping?
Yes.
It's Tae-ha's birthday today.
Wait. Is that so?
Yes.
That's right. Tae-ha's birthday
was around this time of year.
- You're right.
- Today's his birthday.
Oh, I see you're all here.
Jeong-hwa is back.
- Careful.
- Jeong…
- Jeong-hwa.
- Hello.
- I'm back.
- Jeong-hwa.
- Are you feeling better?
- Yes.
While I was hospitalized,
we got to spend time glued to each other,
like newlyweds again.
Thank goodness
the car accident wasn't worse.
- Exactly.
- Yes.
It's Tae-ha's birthday today,
so we hurried over here.
Ma'am, I'll help you with the food later.
- Goodness, no.
- You don't need to help.
We'll help out.
- I'm fine.
- You should rest.
I'll help out too!
Eun-sae!
- Grandma!
- Oh, yes. Goodness me.
Good heavens, what's happening?
Goodness, you're here.
Ms. Prosecutor.
I thought I was Tae-ha's wife here,
not a prosecutor.
What's going on?
I thought you'd never come here again.
That's impossible.
Because our connection…
is like taffy.
That's right.
Welcome back.
- Ladies.
- Welcome back.
- I missed you.
- Me too.
Well done for coming back.
We only got to see you on TV.
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday dear Jang Tae-ha
- Make a wish.
- Go on.
We can hear you.
He's like a kid.
- Happy birthday!
- Happy birthday.
Happy birthday.
Thank you all so much.
Tae-ha, is there anything you want?
It'll be our treat.
Come on, Hui-ja.
What could we possibly give him
that would compare to the gift
he already received?
That's true.
His fake bride has become his real bride.
What gift could possibly top that?
Oh, come on.
You two sure took the long way around.
Now all that's left is for them to live
happily ever after like us.
Now that I think about it,
they're the spitting image.
Sorry?
Who is?
Her and Tae-ha's mom.
Sorry?
Me and Tae-ha's mother?
32 YEARS AGO
Are your feet cold?
How pretty.
Along the fruit farm path
Outside the village
The African flowers are in full bloom
Isn't it "acacia"?
Pardon?
Acacia.
You look like you're from out of town,
not from Gujin.
That's right.
I came after hearing about a dishwashing
job that came with room and board,
but they already hired someone.
How old?
Six months.
No, I meant…
There's a sink full of dishes
back at my place too.
I guess you could stay with me tonight
if you have nowhere else to go.
What are you doing?
Don't stand around.
Lay him in there and get him comfy.
Thank you.
The sunset is so pretty from here!
It's so spectacle.
"Spectacular."
I was planning on going to night school
once the baby's a bit older.
You don't look that old yourself, lady.
I'm 23.
So I'm technically a young lady.
I guess so.
My daughter would be your age
if she were still alive.
And the baby's dad?
He's not around.
I'm raising him on my own.
No parents to rely on?
None.
That's why I'm four in one.
His grandma, grandpa, and dad.
I'll be everything for him.
A baby doesn't need a smart mom
who went to college.
The best mom is one
who showers her baby with love.
I'll cook dinner today to repay you
for letting us stay the night.
Well, if you say so.
Please try it.
Golly, you make a mean gochujang stew.
Where did you learn to make this?
I've just made it a lot.
Because someone likes it.
Didn't you say you're four in one?
You should eat four times as much
so you have the energy to raise your baby.
No one really knows
how my Tae-ha's life will turn out.
Just look at The Last Match.
It looks like
Son Ji-chang's team will win,
but in the end,
Jang Dong-gun makes a dunk,
and his team wins.
Life is like a basketball game.
My Tae-ha may not have the best luck
when it comes to parents,
but who knows if he'll throw down
a huge dunk later in life?
Who says he's unlucky?
Look at those chubby cheeks of his.
They're so chubby,
they might burst any minute.
You're like a skewer,
and yet you've fed him so well.
You can search all over the country.
There aren't many mothers
as admirable as you.
I'm admirable?
Of course.
With no one to rely on, you still
protected your child with all your might.
If you're not an admirable mother, who is?
If you have nowhere to go,
do you want to just stay here
and make taffy with me?
Really?
I'll even throw your baby
a great first birthday party.
Hurry and eat up.
Goodness, I doubt
you're even eating regular meals.
Here, have some hairtail.
HAPPY FIRST BIRTHDAY
The baby is the star of the show.
Why would I dress up?
Please hold still.
A first birthday photo is forever.
His grandma should be pretty.
There.
- That's enough.
- All done.
All right.
Okay.
Let's see what our Tae-ha will pick.
- All right.
- What's your pick?
Okay, Tae-ha.
Which one of these takes your fancy?
Let's grab one.
Good boy. The gavel.
Grab the gavel. Go on.
That's it. Good boy.
She lived a lonely life without any
belongings in the world to call her own,
and yet she never lost heart
and stayed so bright.
And just like a certain someone,
she hated being called "lady."
Seeing you with such a good person
and being so affectionate with her…
I'm sure Tae-ha's mom is smiling
way up there.
Yes.
She's probably smiling with happiness.
- I'm sure she is.
- Yes.
Tae-ha's mom, thank you for the food!
Thank you for the food!
- Let's eat.
- Please eat.
Ma'am, when are you going back to Seoul?
I have to leave soon.
- You're leaving already?
- So soon?
It's not even taffy-making day today,
but I guess the whole village
will smell sickly sweet later.
Oh my goodness!
I told you I'd drive you to Seoul.
I told you I don't want to hassle you.
I told you, I'm fine.
And I told you, I'm really fine.
Just look at them.
I'm going to miss you so much
until the weekend.
Me too.
Hold up.
You said I was the one and only woman
in your life.
Does that mean
this is your first real relationship?
- Yes, he's been single since birth.
- It's his first.
So what if it's my first?
Speaking from experience,
starting tomorrow, people will look at you
like you're a lunatic.
- Looks delicious.
- It does.
- Are you nuts?
- Sorry?
Even an Olympic gold medalist
wouldn't smile as wide as you.
So this is what she meant.
And suddenly,
everything in the world
will look beautiful.
What are you doing? What are you saying?
Hey, Tae-ha!
- Hello.
- Hi.
- A bird pooped on him.
- Bird poop?
- Yeah.
- Oh dear.
That's what bird poop looks like?
Is he smiling?
What, is he that bird expert, Yun Mu-bu?
Why is he looking so lovingly
at bird poop?
Try giving him cow or dog poop.
Right now, even a field of poop
will look like a field of flowers to him.
- Look at this.
- Look at what?
What bird do you think did this?
- Stay away!
- What the heck?
And you'll feel a new sense of gratitude
for the invention of cell phones.
I feel like I can finally breathe,
seeing your face like this.
How did people
from the Goryeo and Joseon periods
endure their lovesickness without phones?
Maybe that's why they died so young.
We'll finally meet up tomorrow.
Yeah. I'm going to stick to you like glue
all day tomorrow.
By the way, what should we
call each other?
- Call each other?
- Yes.
It feels a bit too formal
always calling you "Jang Tae-ha."
Oppa.
Oppa, do you have a hole in your chin?
Oppa, say "ah."
Oppa, you okay?
" Oppa"
is a bit too cliché.
Right. I think so too.
What else is there?
Just call me anything.
I don't care what we call each other.
Really?
Well, okay.
I'll pick you up tomorrow.
Okay.
I'll look so good tomorrow
that I'll blow you away. Just you wait.
Jang Tae-ha.
I missed you.
Me too.
Let's have lots of fun this weekend.
I worked all night yesterday to do that.
I think you're still working hard.
You mean my looks?
Yeah.
Let's hurry and go.
I'll choose the music.
Sure.
It's been a while, so maybe we should
listen to my favorite g.o.d oppas.
Your g.o.d oppas?
Yes.
What's wrong with my g.o.d oppas?
Huh? Nothing.
It's good to hear.
"Oppa"…
is a bit too cliché.
Right. I think so too.
Are we a year apart?
Yes, I'm 33, and you're 34.
Right.
We're so old, aren't we?
Yeah.
But I'm a year older than you, huh?
That's okay.
Stay strong.
And thumbs up, please. All right.
Take the picture. Smile.
That's good.
- Let me see. Did it come out nice?
- Yeah.
It looks good.
Why are we taking pictures?
I have to brag about my friendship
with the star prosecutor.
You could even say that our clinic
produced said star prosecutor.
Right?
Yes, well, thank you.
I probably got my memory back
thanks to your treatment.
As if I'd fall for that.
You remembered.
You know,
it's great that you remembered
and are going back to your old life,
but I'm a little sad
that I won't be able to see you anymore.
Sure, we won't be seeing each other
as doctor and patient,
but our relationship is still precious.
Going forward, I'll consider you my oppa.
What?
Why are you shocked?
Then should we cut ties
because I'm done with treatment?
Yeah, she can consider me her oppa.
Bring it in.
Eun-sae.
Gi-jun oppa?
Hey, that's not bad.
Yeah, that's better.
Isn't it so nice to be back here
after so long?
What's wrong, Jang Tae-ha?
Gi-jun and I
are the same age.
I know.
You two were high school classmates.
Yeah, we were classmates.
I'll get the car.
So cute.
How is he so adorable?
Yesterday, he was all,
"I don't care what we call each other."
Jang Tae-ha, let's go together.
This is good.
Isn't it hard going back and forth
between Taffy Village and Seoul?
It's not hard at all.
All the people I want to see are here.
We went to see someone I'd missed today.
Really? Who?
Gi-jun oppa.
Gi-jun, as in Tae-ha's friend
who treated you?
- Yes.
- I see.
But since he's not treating me anymore,
he's not my doctor.
That makes sense.
That's right.
If we're just talking about looks,
I look older than you,
so I could be your oppa too.
That's true. You're absolutely right.
People who don't know us would think
you're my oppa.
That's right.
Should I just call you oppa then?
Then should we try hearing it?
Gang-rok oppa.
I like that.
What? Why are you getting up
in the middle of eating?
To feed the dog.
Dogs get hungry too.
Come when you're done.
Stop it.
- Yeah.
- You'll make the kid cry.
Did you notice?
Of course we did!
If you had gone on any longer,
you would have called me oppa too.
I just love how that oppa
acts like a blushing teen. He's adorable.
Go and cheer him up. I bet his insides
are more burnt than this scorched rice.
- I'll be right back.
- You don't have to come back.
How can he be such a fool?
Fool. A total fool.
Jang Tae-ha.
How could you go home without me?
I was worried Blessing might be hungry.
Are you sulking right now, Jang Tae-ha?
No! Me?
Even someone riding the bullet train
could see you're sulking.
I'm not though.
You are though.
Do you think I don't know you?
I can tell just by your face, Jang Tae-ha.
The whole "Jang Tae-ha" thing…
Gi-jun is an oppa.
Gang-rok is an oppa. Even g.o.d are oppas.
So why am I the only one…
Well, forget it.
You're really leaving me behind, babe?
I'm asking if you're going alone.
Babe.
I can call anyone "oppa."
"Babe" is so much better.
Don't you think, babe?
Yeah.
Did you want me to call you "oppa"
that badly?
Tae-ha oppa.
Oppa.
Oh, stop it.
Should I?
Then should I call you Jang Tae-ha again?
And speak to you politely?
Come on, oppa! Tae-ha oppa.
Oppa.
Babe.
Seriously.
Oh, come on.
I mean, I like it, but…
But?
It really is home sweet home.
But
what should I call you?
Do I keep calling you "Go Eun-sae"?
What's wrong with that?
I like hearing that name so much.
- Because your mother gave you that name?
- Yes, exactly.
This is just my guess,
but I think my mom dreamt of a pretty bird
when she was pregnant with me.
That could be true.
Right?
I wonder why your mother
named you "Tae-ha."
I don't know.
Maybe she wanted me to become
a strong person
who can embrace everything
like a big river.
But embracing everything and being patient
is really hard to do.
I don't think she wanted her child
to just be strong.
I want to ask her, but I can't.
Where is your mother?
She's in a place
overlooking the entire village.
Let's go see her together sometime.
Okay.
Time goes by too fast when we're together.
I have to go back to Seoul tomorrow.
- You have so much work, right?
- Yeah, until the trial.
Is there anything I can help you with?
There is.
Do you know what Baek Sang-gil
used to do a long time ago?
- A long time ago?
- It was a long time ago.
I found something suspicious
in his office.
SEOUL BIRTH REGISTER
We found this in your safe
while searching your office.
It appears to be a register of births
in Seoul from May 1993 to 1994.
You remember it, right?
I grew up in an orphanage,
so I know how it goes.
The illegal adoption of infants
and trafficking of newborns.
Were you involved
in that sort of thing back then?
I'm going to ask for life imprisonment
for you anyway.
Adding one more crime
won't change your sentence,
so why not just admit it?
Adding one less crime
won't change my sentence either,
so why not just stop digging?
REHABILITATION
It appears to be a register of births
in Seoul from May 1993 to 1994.
You remember it, right?
You're smoking a lot today.
Do you have a lot on your mind?
I guess so.
They keep making me think about
useless memories.
It's all because of one guy.
All of this happened
because he disobeyed me.
Even the memories
that I didn't have to remember.
I should've nipped that trouble
in the bud long ago.
It's time to cut it down.
The first trial
of former Gangju Mayor Ju Min-jong
and Chairman Baek of Mirae Eden
will be held
at the Seoul Eastern District Court
this morning.
The prosecution is being led
by Prosecutor Go Ji-won.
Furthermore, considering the antisocial
charges that have been uncovered,
we seek 15 years' imprisonment
for Ju Min-jong
and life imprisonment for Baek Sang-gil.
Here, just a moment!
Please say a few words!
THE LATE JANG HYE-SU
Mom.
You've been watching everything, right?
I'm sorry for disappointing you until now.
But…
I like how things are now.
Now I'm truly…
happy.
You did a great job
getting through a big case.
It's a shame because it seems like
there are still more crimes to uncover.
They're such old cases
that many of them lack any evidence.
Let's take it slow.
Prosecutor!
Baek Sang-gil escaped
the prison transport van.
What the hell do you mean?
EUN-SAE, HONG DO-YEOP, KIM GANG-ROK
Sir!
- Hurry up.
- What's going on?
- How come you're…
- Baek Sang-gil escaped.
Yeah.
You're okay, right?
Yeah, I'm okay.
I'm under government protection,
and Violent Crimes is heading to Gujin.
Here?
If he escaped to hide or to stow away,
that'd be some relief.
But if he escaped to get revenge,
then Taffy Village could be a target.
Just be careful until then.
I'll join you as soon as things
are settled here.
Nothing suggests
that Baek Sang-gil is headed here.
We're just preparing
for the worst-case scenario.
Don't get scared yet.
Okay.
And Grandma?
What's all that noise?
Okay.
- What about Jang Tae-ha?
- The boys are looking for him.
What is it? Is she not picking up?
No. I can't reach Song-wol either.
GRANDMA
Grandma.
It's been a while.
If you bring the police and make a fuss,
the old woman dies.
Come alone.
No. Don't come! You can't come here!
- Grandma, you okay?
- Tae-ha!
Don't you dare come--
Grandma!
Grandma, can you hear me?
Baek Sang-gil, you bastard.
Sir.
- Let's go around.
- There's no time.
- You can't.
- Coach.
Not alone.
We need at least three for that many.
Everyone, please don't get hurt.
Jang Tae-ha!
Fuck!
Damn it!
Man, this isn't easy.
When she was alive,
she was a mother
who would protect her child with her life.
I'm sure she's protecting her child
from heaven too.
You won't be able to touch Tae-ha.
You won't touch him. Never!
There's something
in this world
that you can never win against.
Grandma!
Why are you here? Why did you come?
- Grandma, I'm here. You're okay now.
- Why would you…
What are you going to do?
It's okay now.
- Be careful.
- It's okay.
- Good heavens.
Oh my goodness.
First off, your favorite things are
boxing and gochujang stew.
I've just made it a lot.
Because someone likes it.
OUR STICKY LOVE
Subtitle translation by: Jimin Choi